CURRICULUM VITAE

Andrea Castricato



PERSONAL INFORMATION

First Name: Andrea
Surname: Castricato
Date of birth: 04/04/1987
Place of birth: Sassari (SS)
Nationality: Italian

Telephone: E-mail:

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

- 2006 Certificate of accounting
- 2011 Youth sports animator course
- 2016 Football Coaching certificate (UEFA B)

INTRODUCTION

Always passionate about football and sports in general. I started playing football very early in the youth academy of Olbia Calcio and then joined the first team with which i made my professional debut. After that i had several experiences in Sardinia with others clubs in non-professional leagues.

I started coaching early and after obtaining the UEFA B licence, i spent several years in the youth academy of Olbia Calcio and Cagliari Calcio. In 2023 i had my first experience working with the first team, as the assistant coach of Mario Petrone in Budoni Calcio team in Serie D, national championship.

Between these two football experience, i emigrated out of Sardinia, living a year in spain and two years in Australia, opportunities which allowed me to learn two lenguages.

I've always beenvery keen on social work, i love travelling and learning about new cultures, i visited many european capitals and other experiences abroad, India, Senegal and east Africa where, in Uganda, i worked several months at the NGO "Deborah Ricciu" as a volunteer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Football player career

STAGIONE	SQUADRA	SERIE
2005/2006	San Teodoro	Eccellenza
2006/2007	Olbia	C2
2007/2008	Olbia	C2
2008/2009	Nuorese	Eccellenza
2009/2010	Muravera	Eccellenza
2010/2011	Olbia	Eccellenza
2011/2012	Olbia	Eccellenza

Work activities

- From 2010 to 2012 sports animator at the Geovillage summer center in Olbia
- From 2014 to 2017 coach at Star Sport football academy
- From 2018 to 2020 coach of U12/U13 at Olbia Calcio 1905
- From 2017 to 2023 coach at Summer Camp Cagliari Calcio during summer season
- From 2019 to 2023 technical coordinator of "Football Accademy" of Cagliari Calcio for the northern aera of Sardinia
- Season 23/24 assistant coach of Budoni Calcio in Serie D
- Since 2017 part of the organization and supervisor of the "Manlio Selis" world tournamet U14 category this year at its 28° edition
- From the 2014 season to date, in the summer season, manager for Costa Eventi (orgaization of sporting events, summer camp specialized in football ad basketball, organization and coordination of various national and international tounaments)

Other experiences

- In 2012 one year in Spain
- From 2012 to 2014 Australian experience in various sectors including sports, ospitality e agricolture
- Between 2016 and 2017 voluteer in Uganda at Ithe primary school "Deborah Ricciu"

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Language(s)

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other Language(s): English (good level) - Spanish (good level)

Computer skills

Good knowledge of the Office packege and Windows

Abilities

Excellent interpersonal and organizational skills Excellent technical skills and ability to work in a team

Driving license

In possession of a valid driving licence category B

Andrea Castricato